<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Messages</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Messages</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Some woman</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-10-29/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-10-29/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;reading&#34;&gt;Reading&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.crosswire.org/study/parallelstudy.jsp?key=Luke+7%3A36#cv&#34;&gt;Luke 7.36-50&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-mission-of-jesus-christ&#34;&gt;The mission of Jesus Christ&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Luke&amp;rsquo;s Gospel tells us that Jesus began his mission by reading from the Book of Isaiah:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Spirit of the Lord is upon me because he has anointed me to preach the gospel to the poor&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;he has sent me to heal the brokenhearted&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;to preach deliverance to the captives and recovery of sight to the blind&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In the beginning (part 2)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-07-07/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-07-07/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A while ago we looked at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.crosswire.org/study/parallelstudy.jsp?key=Genesis+1%3A1#cv&#34;&gt;Genesis chapter 1&lt;/a&gt;, which starts off with the Hebrew words for &lt;em&gt;In the beginning&lt;/em&gt;. Today we will look at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.crosswire.org/study/parallelstudy.jsp?key=John+1%3A1#cv&#34;&gt;John chapter 1, verse 1&lt;/a&gt;, which starts off with the Greek words for &lt;em&gt;In the beginning&lt;/em&gt;. Here&amp;rsquo;s a picture of the beginning of John&amp;rsquo;s Gospel in a manuscript called P66, dated around 200 AD:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/Beginning_P66.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;John 1 in P66 (~200 AD)&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bible Code</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-06-08/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-06-08/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Now about that time Herod the king laid hands on some who belonged to the church, to do them harm. And he had James the brother of John executed with a sword. When he saw that it pleased the Jews, he proceeded to arrest Peter as well. (Now these were the days of Unleavened Bread.) When he had arrested him, he put him in prison, turning him over to four squads of soldiers to guard him, intending only after the Passover to bring him before the people. So Peter was kept in the prison, but prayer for him was being made to God intensely by the church.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Valley</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-04-29/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-04-29/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When I was young I went to church every week with my family. Being a Western Australian Presbyterian Church, it had Scottish blood. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kbGsIVeKU_E&#34;&gt;The Lord&amp;rsquo;s my Shepherd&lt;/a&gt; was sung very often, always to the tune Crimond. Even as a six year old I knew some of it, though I didn&amp;rsquo;t get the first line.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-lords-my-shepherd&#34;&gt;The Lord&amp;rsquo;s my Shepherd&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here is the King James Version of Psalm 23:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In the beginning (part 1)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-02-09/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-02-09/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;earth-rise&#34;&gt;Earth rise&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In December 1968, three astronauts were orbiting the moon when they saw something amazing &amp;ndash; the earth rising above the moon&amp;rsquo;s horizon. They snapped some shots, one of which became the iconic &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dE-vOscpiNc&#34;&gt;Earthrise&lt;/a&gt;. Later that day (though it&amp;rsquo;s a bit hard to define what &lt;em&gt;day&lt;/em&gt; means when you&amp;rsquo;re orbiting the moon), the astronauts broadcast a message to &lt;em&gt;the largest audience that had ever listened to a human voice&lt;/em&gt;. NASA had told them to &lt;em&gt;do something appropriate&lt;/em&gt;, and they decided to read from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ToHhQUhdyBY&#34;&gt;the first chapter of Genesis&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blessed</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-01-29/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-01-29/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;readings&#34;&gt;Readings&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;hebrew-bible&#34;&gt;Hebrew Bible&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With what shall I come before the Lord, and bow myself before God on high? Shall I come before him with burnt-offerings, with calves a year old? Will the Lord be pleased with thousands of rams, with tens of thousands of rivers of oil? Shall I give my firstborn for my transgression, the fruit of my body for the sin of my soul?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;He has told you, O mortal, what is good; and what does the Lord require of you but to do justice, and to love kindness, and to walk humbly with your God?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I must stay at your house today</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2022-10-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2022-10-30/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;readings&#34;&gt;Readings&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;hebrew-bible&#34;&gt;Hebrew Bible&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.crosswire.org/study/parallelstudy.jsp?key=Isaiah+1%3A10#cv&#34;&gt;Isaiah 1.10-18 NASB&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hear the word of the LORD, you rulers of Sodom! Listen to the teaching of our God, you people of Gomorrah! What to me is the multitude of your sacrifices? says the LORD; I have had enough of burnt offerings of rams and the fat of fed beasts; I do not delight in the blood of bulls, or of lambs, or of goats. When you come to appear before me, who asked this from your hand?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Life after life</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2022-10-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2022-10-13/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today&amp;rsquo;s topic is life after death, or, to put it another way, life after life. I know as much as the next person on this topic (not very much). There will therefore be a lot of questions for us to try to answer.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-life&#34;&gt;What is life?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The first question is, &lt;em&gt;What is life?&lt;/em&gt; How would you define life? Let&amp;rsquo;s try to come up with a general answer that covers all kinds of life, including God&amp;rsquo;s life.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Anabaptists</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2022-08-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2022-08-11/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Five hundred years ago, one man asked another man to baptize him. So began the story of the Anabaptists. The &lt;em&gt;what&lt;/em&gt; Baptists? The Anabaptists. &amp;ldquo;Ana-&amp;rdquo; in Greek is the same as &amp;ldquo;Re-&amp;rdquo; in English &amp;ndash; &lt;em&gt;Anabaptist&lt;/em&gt; means &lt;em&gt;Rebaptizer&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;gutenberg&#34;&gt;Gutenberg&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Johannes_Gutenberg&#34;&gt;Johannes Gutenberg&lt;/a&gt; introduced the movable type printing press to Europe around the year 1450 AD:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In Renaissance Europe, the arrival of mechanical movable type printing introduced the era of mass communication which permanently altered the structure of society. The relatively unrestricted circulation of information—including revolutionary ideas—transcended borders, captured the masses in the Reformation, and threatened the power of political and religious authorities; the sharp increase in literacy broke the monopoly of the literate elite on education and learning and bolstered the emerging middle class. Across Europe, the increasing cultural self-awareness of its people led to the rise of proto-nationalism, accelerated by the flowering of the European vernacular languages to the detriment of Latin&amp;rsquo;s status as lingua franca. In the 19th century, the replacement of the hand-operated Gutenberg-style press by steam-powered rotary presses allowed printing on an industrial scale, while Western-style printing was adopted all over the world, becoming practically the sole medium for modern bulk printing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Athanasius against the world</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2022-06-23/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2022-06-23/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today we will hear about a theological controversy that split the Christian world. It started around 318 AD as a dispute between two members of the Egyptian church but soon spread around the Mediterranean.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-setting&#34;&gt;The setting&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To give a bit of background, Christianity had only just been legalized. Just under three hundred years earlier, Christians began spreading the message of Jesus Christ. One early statement of faith was summarized in a five letter acronym that spelled out the Greek word for fish (ΙΧΘΥΣ):&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mission 101</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2022-05-29/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2022-05-29/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;lectionary-readings&#34;&gt;Lectionary readings&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://lectionary.library.vanderbilt.edu/texts.php?id=140&#34;&gt;Seventh Sunday after Easter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://crosswire.org/study/parallelstudy.jsp?key=Psalms+97%3A1#cv&#34;&gt;Psalm 97&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://crosswire.org/study/parallelstudy.jsp?key=Acts+16%3A16#cv&#34;&gt;Acts 16.18-34&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://crosswire.org/study/parallelstudy.jsp?key=Revelation+of+John+22%3A12#cv&#34;&gt;Revelation 22.12-21&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://crosswire.org/study/parallelstudy.jsp?key=John+17%3A20#cv&#34;&gt;John 17.20-26&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;lord-most-high&#34;&gt;Lord Most High&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Verse seven of Psalm 97 says:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For You are the Lord Most High over all the earth;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You are exalted far above all gods.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Many agree that there is one God, though not everyone. There are places around the world today where people think that there are many gods &amp;ndash; one for this and one for that. If something goes wrong here then you have to pray to that god over there, if you want to find out about such and such then you have to go and consult the god who lives at so and so. It&amp;rsquo;s complicated. This is the kind of world view that prevailed at a place called Philippi in what we now call Greece when Paul, Silas, Timothy, and Luke arrived there.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>You give them something to eat</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2022-05-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2022-05-02/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tonight we will look at the miracle of the five loaves and two fish from Mark&amp;rsquo;s Gospel.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;marks-gospel&#34;&gt;Mark&amp;rsquo;s Gospel&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Concerning this Gospel, a man named &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Papias_of_Hierapolis&#34;&gt;Papias&lt;/a&gt;, who was Bishop of Hierapolis (modern day &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pamukkale&#34;&gt;Pamukkale in Turkey&lt;/a&gt;), wrote the following:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mark, indeed, having been the interpreter of Peter, wrote accurately, howbeit not in order, all that he recalled of what was either said or done by the Lord. For he neither heard the Lord, nor was he a follower of his, but, at a later date (as I said), of Peter; who used to adapt his instructions to the needs [of the moment], but not with a view to putting together the Dominical oracles in orderly fashion: so Mark did no wrong in thus writing some things as he recalled them. For he kept a single aim in view: not to omit anything of what he heard, nor to state anything therein falsely.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The weeping prophet</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2022-01-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2022-01-30/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-life-of-jeremiah&#34;&gt;A life of Jeremiah&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The first reading today was the call of Jeremiah. Some of you might remember a song called &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IgKejlrT-sI&#34;&gt;Jeremiah was a bullfrog&lt;/a&gt;. Here&amp;rsquo;s something you might not know about that song:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Some of the words are nonsensical. Axton [who wrote the song] wanted to persuade his record producers to record a new melody he had written, and the producers asked him to sing any words to the tune. A member of Three Dog Night [the band that sang it] said that the original lyrics to the song were &amp;ldquo;Jeremiah was a prophet&amp;rdquo; but no one liked it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Writing letters in the olden days</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2021-11-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2021-11-11/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-graeco-roman-letter-form&#34;&gt;The Graeco-Roman letter form&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You know you are in a theology lesson when you hear someone start talking about the Graeco-Roman letter form.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here is a letter writing pattern we tend to use these days:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Dear &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Blah, blah, blah&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yours sincerely,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We put the person&amp;rsquo;s name at the start and our own name at the end.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Walking home to God&#39;s country</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2021-10-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2021-10-31/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the days of the Judges famine came to the land and a certain man from Bethlehem of Judah went &amp;ndash; he, his wife and his two sons &amp;ndash; to live in the country of Moab.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;[Ruth 1.1 JB]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Alleluia! Praise the Lord, my soul.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;[Psalm 146.1 JB]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But now Christ has made his appearance as a high priest bringing benefits that have come about through the greater and more perfect tent which wasn&amp;rsquo;t crafted by human hands, that is, which didn&amp;rsquo;t originate with the created order.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why don&#39;t ladies wear hats in church anymore?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2021-09-09/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2021-09-09/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you are old enough then you will remember a time when a lot of ladies wore hats in church. Nowadays there are still churches where the adult women wear hats; the Cook Island Churches are a good example. However, most churches don&amp;rsquo;t practice this any more. Why is that so?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-wear-hats&#34;&gt;Why wear hats?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The first question is, why did women wear hats in the first place? It&amp;rsquo;s probably to do with something that Paul said:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Lord&#39;s Prayer</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2021-08-29/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2021-08-29/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today we are going to abandon the usual lectionary reading (which is from Mark&amp;rsquo;s Gospel) and instead look at Matthew&amp;rsquo;s Gospel. That&amp;rsquo;s because we have been hearing about the bread of heaven over the last few weeks, which inspired me to talk about the Lord&amp;rsquo;s Prayer.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-bit-missing&#34;&gt;A bit missing?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Lord&amp;rsquo;s Prayer may well be the best known piece of scripture in the Universe, but what does it actually say? Don&amp;rsquo;t worry, we are not going to look at the grammatical analysis of each word in Greek to discover that some of the requests are aorist, active, third person, singular, imperative verbs, and things like that. Instead we will look at the structure of the Lord&amp;rsquo;s Prayer to see what might be the central point.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atomic grace</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2021-02-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2021-02-14/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For Phoebe, who encouraged me to write this down.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;And you shall eat and be satisfied, and bless the LORD your God for the good land which he has given you.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mechon-mamre.org/p/pt/pt0508.htm#10&#34;&gt;Deuteronomy 8.10&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For these and all thy mercies, Lord make us truly thankful.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thank you for this food, and for the hands that prepared it. Thank you for the people who worked to give us this food. Thank you for the tractors they drove and the farms they ploughed. Thank you for the seeds they planted and the rain you sent to water them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lifted up</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2021-05-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2021-05-30/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today is Trinity Sunday, and we will be looking at the part of John&amp;rsquo;s Gospel that talks about one night when a man named Nicodemus went to talk to Jesus.  The part is chapter 3, verses 1 to 17, which includes those famous words:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For God so loved the world, that He gave His only begotten Son, that whoever believes in Him shall not perish, but have eternal life. [John 3.16 NASB]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s this?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2021-01-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2021-01-31/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-deep-impression&#34;&gt;A deep impression&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Today&amp;rsquo;s lectionary reading from Mark talks about what happened when Jesus went to church one day. He caused a bit of a stir.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;They went as far as Capernaum, and as soon as the sabbath came he went to the synagogue and began to teach. And his teaching made a deep impression on them because, unlike the scribes, he taught them with authority.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;[Mark 1.21-22 Jerusalem Bible]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>For those who trust him</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2020-11-29/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2020-11-29/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;isaiah-64&#34;&gt;Isaiah 64&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Today&amp;rsquo;s reading is from Isaiah chapter 64:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Oh that you would tear the heavens open and come down&#xA;--at your Presence the mountains would melt,&#xA;as fire sets brushwood alight,&#xA;as fire causes water to boil--&#xA;to make known your name to your enemies,&#xA;and make the nations tremble at your Presence,&#xA;working unexpected miracles&#xA;such as no one has ever heard of before.&#xA;No ear has heard,&#xA;no eye has seen&#xA;any god act like this&#xA;for those who trust him.&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pr</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The concept of the Jubilee Year in the Bible</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2020-05-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2020-05-14/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-we-will-cover-today&#34;&gt;What we will cover today&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;What is a Jubilee?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s it doing in the Bible?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The Jubilee in the Old Testament&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The Jubilee in translation&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The Jubilee in the New Testament&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;What would a Jubilee look like today?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-a-jubilee&#34;&gt;What is a Jubilee?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What do you think of when you hear the word &lt;em&gt;Jubilee&lt;/em&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Many of us think of a significant royal or national anniversary.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;whats-it-doing-in-the-bible&#34;&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s it doing in the Bible?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There is a Jubilee in the Bible. You can read about it in the Book of Leviticus. The idea of the Jubilee pops up in other places as well. If you know about the Jubilee, some of the things Jesus said make more sense.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Sign of Jonah</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2019-04-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2019-04-20/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I got the idea for this message from my friend Tom Shackles, who was taken away from us in a whirlwind.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/Shacks.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Tom Shackles&#34; title=&#34;Tom Shackles&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thank you all for being here. Today I&amp;rsquo;d like to talk about the Easter holidays. I&amp;rsquo;m not going to talk about these Easter holidays but about the original Easter holy days, three days that changed everything.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;give-us-a-sign&#34;&gt;Give us a sign&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In chapter twelve of Matthew&amp;rsquo;s Gospel we find Jesus in a dispute with the religious authorities. Here&amp;rsquo;s how it happened:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cups of wine</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2019-03-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2019-03-30/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What Christians now call &lt;em&gt;communion&lt;/em&gt; or the &lt;em&gt;Last Supper&lt;/em&gt; began as a Passover Meal that Jesus shared with his disciples the night before he was crucified. Jesus told his disciples to remember him whenever they had that meal. At a previous service we looked at certain aspects of the bread. Tonight we will look at certain aspects of the wine.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Passover meal has four cups of wine but we will only have two cups tonight. We will drink grape juice, which is just as well because too many cups of wine put you over the limit. There will be something to remember about Jesus for each cup.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Poor man&#39;s bread</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2019-02-23/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2019-02-23/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;bread-and-wine&#34;&gt;Bread and wine&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What Christians call &lt;em&gt;communion&lt;/em&gt; or the &lt;em&gt;Lord&amp;rsquo;s supper&lt;/em&gt; started off as a &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Passover_Seder&#34;&gt;Passover meal&lt;/a&gt; that Jesus ate with his disciples on the night before he went to the cross.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/last_supper.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;The Last Supper&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;During communion we eat something like bread and drink something like wine. Communion is a symbolic meal, and tonight we will look at the symbolism of the bread. Next month I hope to look at the symbolism of the wine.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beautiful feet</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2019-02-09/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2019-02-09/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tonight we will look at something from Luke&amp;rsquo;s Gospel, which tells us about what happened once when Jesus was invited to a meal. Here is how it starts:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of the Pharisees invited him to a meal. When he arrived at the Pharisee&amp;rsquo;s house and took his place at table, a woman came in, who had a bad name in the town. She had heard he was dining with the Pharisee and had brought with her an alabaster jar of ointment. She waited behind him at his feet, weeping, and her tears fell on his feet, and she wiped them away with her hair; then she covered his feet with kisses and anointed them with the ointment. [Luke 7.36-38, Jerusalem Bible]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The evil eye</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2018-12-29/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2018-12-29/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-ten-commandments&#34;&gt;The ten commandments&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Our church has been going through the ten commandments and now we have reached the last one. God gave these commandments to the Israelites after he set them free. The commandments tell us how to honour God and respect each other. A country that obeys these commands will be set free, but any nation that ignores them is in danger of reverting to slavery.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The children of Israel had just been set free from Egypt. Over the last four hundred years they had gone from a position of great privilege to the worst possible situation; they began as guests of Egypt&amp;rsquo;s governor (namely Joseph) and ended up as slaves who toiled under the Egyptian sun making bricks for Pharoah. Only a slave knows what it is like to spend your entire life working hard for someone else, then to end your days with nothing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This little light</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2018-10-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2018-10-13/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;telling-gods-story&#34;&gt;Telling God&amp;rsquo;s story&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Christians are meant to be evangelists. That means we are meant to tell people the good news. The word &lt;em&gt;evangelist&lt;/em&gt; comes from the Greek ευαγγελιον, which means &lt;em&gt;good news&lt;/em&gt;. The word &lt;em&gt;gospel&lt;/em&gt; also means &lt;em&gt;good news&lt;/em&gt; but has German ancestry (as do a lot of English words).^[The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.merriam-webster.com/dictionary/gospel&#34;&gt;Merriam-Webster&lt;/a&gt; dictionary says, &amp;ldquo;Middle English, from Old English gōdspel (translation of Late Latin evangelium), from &lt;em&gt;gōd&lt;/em&gt; good + &lt;em&gt;spell&lt;/em&gt; tale&amp;rdquo;.]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gentleness</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2018-08-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2018-08-04/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We have been hearing about a well known part of Paul&amp;rsquo;s Letter to the Galatians, where he says:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But the fruit of the Spirit is love, joy, peace, patience, kindness, goodness, faithfulness, gentleness, self-control; against such things there is no law.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://crosswire.org/study/parallelstudy.jsp?key=Galatians+5%3A22#cv&#34;&gt;Gal 5.22-23&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Galatians were &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Celts&#34;&gt;Celts&lt;/a&gt;, the same people whose descendants still live in Scotland, Ireland, and Wales. What were they doing all the way over in Asia Minor? Well, you can look that up on &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Celtic_settlement_of_Eastern_Europe&#34;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;. They were a completely different culture to the others living around there &amp;ndash; different language, different beliefs, different hair. They even had a reputation as head hunters. Paul doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to have been frightened of them though. In fact, he was not afraid to tell them they were stupid!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1 Peter 1.1</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2018-06-09/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2018-06-09/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;a-general-letter&#34;&gt;A general letter&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The First Letter of Peter is one of the seven General Letters in the New Testament: James; First and Second Peter; First, Second, and Third John; and Jude. These letters are called &amp;ldquo;General&amp;rdquo; because they are addressed to general groups of people instead of particular ones. Here&amp;rsquo;s an example of a general letter:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;To Everyone living in Australia, treat foreigners as well as you treat your own people and love them as much as you love yourself. Remember, you were once foreigners in the land of Egypt. I am the LORD your God.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Astonished</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2018-04-07/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2018-04-07/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We have been looking at what the Four Gospels say about what happened on Easter Sunday, and this week we are looking at Mark&amp;rsquo;s account.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mark&amp;rsquo;s Gospel appears to be an eye witness account of Jesus from the time he chose his first followers to when they ran away.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Eusebius, who wrote a history of the church around 300 AD, tells us what someone named &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Papias_of_Hierapolis&#34;&gt;Papias&lt;/a&gt; wrote about Mark. Papias lived from about 60 to 130 AD in a place called &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hierapolis&#34;&gt;Hierapolis&lt;/a&gt; in the Roman province of Asia Minor, which is now part of Turkey. This Papias was a bishop whose lifetime covered the period from when the Gospels were written to when Asia Minor had become a major centre of Christianity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One thing worth pursuing</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2018-01-27/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2018-01-27/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;a-letter-from-prison&#34;&gt;A letter from prison&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve been going through Paul&amp;rsquo;s Letter to the Philippians and today we are up to chapter three. Paul wrote this letter from prison, and he seems to have doubts about getting out alive: &lt;em&gt;To me life means Christ and death means gain&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://crosswire.org/study/parallelstudy.jsp?key=Philippians+1%3A21#cv&#34;&gt;Phil 1.21&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Some think he was in prison in Rome, others in Ephesus, and others in Caesarea. I think the Letter fits well with his imprisonment in Caesarea after being arrested in the temple at Jerusalem. You can read about the surrounding events in Acts chapters 21 to 26. The religious establishment in Israel, who the New Testament calls &lt;em&gt;The Jews&lt;/em&gt;, was after Paul and wanted him dead. (The establishment &lt;em&gt;Jews&lt;/em&gt; of the New Testament should not be confused with the Jews of today &amp;ndash; when you hear &lt;em&gt;Jews&lt;/em&gt; in the New Testament, think of a powerful religious establishment that regards Christianity as a heresy.) Paul used to be one of the religious establishment until something strange happened to him on the road to Damascus. (See &lt;a href=&#34;https://crosswire.org/study/parallelstudy.jsp?key=Acts+9%3A3#cv&#34;&gt;Acts 9.3-9&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>XXIII</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2017-11-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2017-11-12/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;a-favourite&#34;&gt;A favourite&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Psalms are one of the best-loved parts of the Bible, and one of the best-loved Psalms is Psalm 23 (XXIII in Roman numerals). &amp;ldquo;Psalm&amp;rdquo; means &amp;ldquo;song&amp;rdquo;, so what better way to introduce it than to sing it?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;The Lord’s my Shepherd, I’ll not want.&#xA;He makes me down to lie&#xA;In pastures green; He leadeth me&#xA;The quiet waters by.&#xA;&#xA;My soul He doth restore again;&#xA;And me to walk doth make&#xA;Within the paths of righteousness,&#xA;Even for His own Name’s sake.&#xA;&#xA;Yea, though I walk through death’s dark vale,&#xA;Yet will I fear no ill;&#xA;For Thou art with me; and Thy rod&#xA;And staff me comfort still.&#xA;&#xA;My table Thou hast furnishèd&#xA;In presence of my foes;&#xA;My head Thou dost with oil anoint,&#xA;And my cup overflows.&#xA;&#xA;Goodness and mercy all my life&#xA;Shall surely follow me;&#xA;And in God’s house forevermore&#xA;My dwelling place shall be.&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pr</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First words</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2016-08-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2016-08-10/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;four-gospels&#34;&gt;Four Gospels&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Four Gospels are four versions of the Good News concerning Jesus Christ. In them the first generation of Christians tell us what they witnessed when Jesus came to town.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We have been handed four Gospels, those according to Matthew, Mark, Luke, and John. These are the written accounts of the Good News concerning Jesus Christ handed down to us by the first generation of Christians. They are from the time of the apostles, and can be linked with four early Christian leaders (or the missions they headed): James the Just, first bishop of Jerusalem; Peter, taking the Gospel to Jews beyond the Holy Land; Paul, apostle to the Gentiles (i.e. non-Jews); and John, the &amp;ldquo;disciple who Jesus loved&amp;rdquo;. At Galatians 2.9 Paul writes &amp;ldquo;recognizing the grace that had been given to me, James and Cephas and John, who were reputed to be pillars, gave to me and Barnabas the right hand of fellowship&amp;rdquo;. Cephas is better known to us as Peter. Adding Paul himself to the three &amp;ldquo;pillars&amp;rdquo; gives us the four. With the possible exception of Jude, the entire New Testament is attributable to these four or the missions they headed. Even Jude can be associated with James the Just, Jude being his brother.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Galatians</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2015-12-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2015-12-01/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;You stupid Galatians! Who put the evil eye on you?&amp;rdquo; That&amp;rsquo;s what Paul says in his letter to the Galatians. Wikipedia says &amp;ldquo;The Galatians were a Celtic people that dwelt mainly in the north central regions of Asia Minor or Anatolia, in what was known as Galatia, in today&amp;rsquo;s Turkey.&amp;quot;^[Wikipedia, &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Galatians_%28people%29&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Galatians (people)&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;.] Back then people who spoke Celtic languages could be found all the way from Scotland in the West to the Roman province of Galatia in the East. They were also head hunters.^[Wikipedia, &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Celts&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Celts&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;.]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Genuine love</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2015-04-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2015-04-11/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;no-one-is-right&#34;&gt;No one is right&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The greatest proof that the Bible is inspired is that it has withstood so much bad preaching! &amp;ndash; A. T. Robertson&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;No one is right, no one. All have gone wrong. Jews and non-Jews alike have a problem &amp;ndash; they do not measure up to their own standards, let alone God&amp;rsquo;s. What can we do about this? Make a big sacrifice? No, it&amp;rsquo;s not enough. All we can do is believe God like Abraham did, and that makes us right with God.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jesus Christ&#39;s Mission</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2013-06-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2013-06-15/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;jesus-announces-his-mission&#34;&gt;Jesus announces his mission&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Gospel of Luke tells us that Jesus&amp;rsquo;s public work began after his baptism by John the Baptist in the Jordan River. People thought that John the Baptist might be the Messiah, the promised saviour of Israel. So John told them this:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I baptize by immersing you in water. However, someone who is stronger than I am is coming; I am not worthy even to release the straps on his sandals. He will baptize you by immersing you in the Holy Spirit and in fire.^[Luke 3.16. New Testament quotations are from Richard K. Moore&amp;rsquo;s new translation, &lt;em&gt;Under the Southern Cross: The New Testament in Australian English&lt;/em&gt;, abbreviated USC from this point forwards.]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Synoptic Gospels</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2013-05-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2013-05-15/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;much-in-common&#34;&gt;Much in common&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Matthew, Mark, and Luke make up the three synoptic Gospels. These three have much in common but have unique elements as well. (Synoptic means “a general view, or a collection of heads or parts so arranged as to exhibit a general view of the whole.”)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Based on this chart^[Wikipedia, “Synoptic Gospels”], would you venture to suggest a solution to the synoptic problem?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/synoptics.png&#34; alt=&#34;Relations between synoptic gospels&#34; title=&#34;Relations between synoptic gospels&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Christian secrets</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2013-03-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2013-03-04/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;christians-keeping-secrets&#34;&gt;Christians keeping secrets&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This Bible study looks at a few parts of the New Testament which hint that the first Christians were keeping some secrets. The initial trigger for this study was a sentence in the Acts of the Apostles that Karen Jobes pointed out in her commentary on 1 Peter.^[Karen H. Jobes, &lt;em&gt;1 Peter&lt;/em&gt; (Grand Rapids: Baker, 2005).] This sentence has been an eye-opener for me, a key to understanding some otherwise puzzling aspects of the New Testament.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Who Is Greatest?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2012-11-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2012-11-18/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I love Mark&amp;rsquo;s Gospel. An early Christian named Papias said that&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mark, having been Peter&amp;rsquo;s interpreter, wrote accurately though not in order all that he recalled of what was either said or done by the Lord. For he neither heard the Lord nor was he a follower of his but at a later date of Peter; who used to adapt his instuctions to the needs of the moment but not with a view to putting together the Lord&amp;rsquo;s sayings in orderly fashion: so that Mark did no wrong in thus writing some things as he recalled them. For he kept a single aim in view: not to omit anything of what he heard nor to state anything therein falsely.^[Adapted from J. Stevenson and W. H. C. Frend (eds.), &lt;em&gt;A New Eusebius&lt;/em&gt; (rev. ed.; London: SPCK, 1987) 49.]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Four pillars</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2012-07-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2012-07-15/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;four-early-leaders&#34;&gt;Four early leaders&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before I became a Christian I used to study a book called &lt;em&gt;The Three Pillars of Zen&lt;/em&gt;. The subtitle tells us that these three pillars are teaching, practice, and enlightenment.^[Philip Kapleau (ed.), &lt;em&gt;The Three Pillars of Zen: Teaching, Practice, and Enlightenment&lt;/em&gt; (Anchor Books, 1980).] Since becoming a Christian I have been studying another book, the New Testament, which began as twenty-seven individual writings that were later collected into four parts:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gospel wheel</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011-08-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011-08-03/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;an-old-christian-symbol&#34;&gt;An old Christian symbol&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here is a picture.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/wheel.png&#34; alt=&#34;Gospel wheel&#34; title=&#34;Gospel wheel&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What do you think it is? It is actually a very old Christian symbol which represents a very good summary of the Gospel.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/acrostic.png&#34; alt=&#34;Gospel wheel unpacked&#34; title=&#34;Gospel wheel unpacked&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you look closely, you might see that these Greek letters are contained in the wheel:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ι (iota)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One page</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2010-10-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2010-10-04/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;one-page-of-one-book&#34;&gt;One page of one book&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sometimes people ask what book you would like to have if stuck on a desert island. These days many would prefer to take their favourite handheld device. That would be good until the batteries ran out unless you were lucky enough to have a solar-powered battery charger too. In some ways books are a better technology than electronic devices. You can drop them, leave them in the rain, or get sand in them and they still work.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Things I have found out about God</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2010-08-22/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2010-08-22/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;an-honour&#34;&gt;An honour&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I am honoured to be able to speak at one of your final assemblies as Manning Uniting Church. I grew up among the people in this church and you played an important part in my upbringing. Despite being disinclined to listen, I heard the oracles of God from an early age. Not that I thought much of them at the time.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Today&amp;rsquo;s message is called “Things I have found out about God,” and there are a number of them so I had better hurry up.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On Christian communities</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2006-08-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2006-08-15/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip; on this rock I will build my church. — Jesus Christ [Matt 16.18]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The church is not a building but a Christian community built on the foundation of faith in Jesus Christ. In other words, it is a community of people who are convinced that Jesus Christ is the Messiah, the Son of the living God. A great deal of Christ&amp;rsquo;s teaching only makes sense in a community context. When he says &amp;ldquo;you,&amp;rdquo; he is often saying &amp;ldquo;you&amp;rdquo; plural, but this is lost in translation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
